Guide to the The Nick Zedd Papers, 1963 - 2016 MSS.311
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series X: Audio
  Series X: Audio includes original audio elements by and or about Nick Zedd, and is organized chronologically, then alphabetically.
  Subseries A: Film Soundtracks include Zedd production sound effects reels.
  Subseries B: Cassettes preserve Zedd's sound work and interview recordings.
  Subseries C: Miscellaneous includes recordings from Zedd's personal collection.
  Subseries D: Vinyl includes Zedd's work with the Zyklon Beatles and other commercial recordings from his personal collection.
  - Subseries A: Film Soundtracks
    Access Copies may not be available, please ask a Fales archivist.
    - "Police State - B28 G #6, 1st Y2 Police Station", 1987; ID: 311.0017 (Film 311.0017)
    - "Police State - City Tone", 1987; ID: 311.0018 (Film 311.0018)
    - "Police State - TTE - 1 #2, 2 Minutes Traffic", 1987; ID: 311.0019 (Film 311.0019)
    - "Police State - Eerie Tone R3 - 13", 1987; ID: 311.0020 (Film 311.0020)
    - "Police State - W.T. Tone Loop", 1987; ID: 311.0021 (Film 311.0021)
    - "Police State - City Pres. TTE1 - 2", 1987; ID: 311.0022 (Film 311.0022)
    - "Police State - E3-C #9 2x Sirens", 1987; ID: 311.0023 (Film 311.0023)
    - "Police State - MS-3 #1 Groan", 1987; ID: 311.0024 (Film 311.0024)
    - "Police State - Track Dupe HD", 1987; ID: 311.0025 (Film 311.0025)
    - "Police State - Wild Sound HD", 1987; ID: 311.0027 (Film 311.0027)
    - "Police State - Sound 43 Filp Extra Transfer", 1987; ID: 311.0029 (Film 311.0029)
    - "Police State - Unmarked Reel", 1987; ID: 311.0030 (Film 311.0030)
    - "Police State - Scene Two Dailies TRK HD", 1987; ID: 311.0031 (Film 311.0031)
    - "Police State" [Unmarked Reel], 1987; ID: 311.0052 (Film 311.0052)
    - "Police State" [Unmarked Reel], 1987; ID: 311.0055 (Film 311.0055)
    - "Why Do You Exist" [Unmarked Reel], 1998; ID: 311.0076 (Film 311.0076)
  - Subseries B: Cassettes
    - "The Giant Fly Invincible - Master", 1971; ID: 311.0471 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0471)
      Format: Dynasound Cassette
    - "Attack & Return of the Giant Fly," "Psycolor", 1968 - 1970; ID: 311.0472 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0472)
      Format: Denon DX1 Cassette
    - "The Perfect Woman" by Nick Zedd with "Dear Nick", c1983; ID: 311.0473 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0473)
      This element was originally found with "The Wild World of Lydia Lunch" film original.
      Format: TDK D90 Cassette
    - "Lydia Lunch - Copy B", c1983; ID: 311.0474 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0474)
      Format: Maxell C90 Cassette
    - "Zedd, Kern Interview", February 16, 1986; ID: 311.0475 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0475)
      Format: Qantem C60 Cassette
    - A) "Nick Zedd Interview," B)"Zedd/Turner Noise Music", 1986; ID: 311.0482 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0482)
      Format: TDK AD90 Cassette
    - "Nick Zedd Interview, WZBC", December 9, 1988; ID: 311.0476 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0476)
      Format: Maxell UR60 Cassette
    - "Nick Zedd Interview, KXLU LA", July 24, 1992; ID: 311.0477 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0477)
      Format: Maxwell UDII 90 Cassette
    - "Kajtek Zedd, Nick Zedd Reads Walt Whitman", 1993; ID: 311.0478 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0478)
      Format: Memorex dBS Cassette
    - "Guys on Film: Geoffrey O'Brien and Nick Zedd" with "The Poetry Project", January 7, 1994; ID: 311.0479 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0479)
    - "Zedd Radio Interview, Switzerland", October 9, 1998; ID: 311.0480 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0480)
      Format: Maxell UDI CD 60 Cassette
    - "Annie Sprinkle: Does Zedd Speak", undated; ID: 311.0481 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0481)
      Format: Maxell XLII Cassette
    - "Zedd", undated; ID: 311.0483 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0483)
      Format: TDK IECI/Type I Cassette
  - Subseries C: Miscellaneous
    - [Commercial CDs], c1985 - 2010 (Box 31)
      This is a collection of 19 CD commercial recordings from Zedd's personal library.
      Format: CD
    - "Kiss Me Now" by Brenda Bergman and the Bodacious Ta-tas, 1995; ID: 311.0484 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0484)
      Format: Cassette
    - [Nick Zedd, Phoebe Gloeckner, and Shannon Wheeler Interviews], January 8, 2001; ID: 311.0487 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0487)
    - "Jared Whitham Music (Danger Child at Play)", undated; ID: 311.0503 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0503)
      Format: CD-R
    - "November Percussion" by Hurst Holt, undated; ID: 311.0504 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0504)
    - [Untitled Message Cassette], undated; ID: 311.0486 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0486)
      Format: Microcassette
    - "Worm Movie", undated; ID: 311.0485 (Box 31, Media ID: 311.0485)
  - Subseries D: Vinyl
    - [Commercial Vinyl], 1969 - 2000 (Box 31, Folder 1 - 8)
      This is a collection of 9 commercial vinyl recordings from Zedd's personal library.
      Format: 7" Vinyl
    - "Consume and Die: Generation Z" by Nick Zedd / Zyklon Beatles, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Media ID: 311.0505
    - "Karen Black", 1990 (Box 31, Folder 10)
      This is the musical work of Zedd's contemporary Kembra Pfahler.
      Media ID: 311.0506
    - "Menace Dement", 1990 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      This is the musical work of Zedd's contemporary Casandra Stark.
      Media ID: 311.0507
- Series XI: Data Storage
  Series XI: Data Storage includes Zedd's magnetic and optical computer data storage elements organized chronologically, then alphabetically.
  Born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - "Nick Zedd in Denmark, #1" by Gritt U.J., May 1999; ID: 311.3.0001 (Box 12, Media ID: 311.3.0001)
    Format: 3 1/2" Gray Verbatim Disk
    Capacity: [unknown]
  - "Nick Zedd in Denmark, #2" by Gritt U.J., May 1999; ID: 311.3.0002 (Box 12, Media ID: 311.3.0002)
  - "Zedd Cast on Set, Marguerite", July 12, 2003; ID: 311.3.0003 (Box 12, Media ID: 311.3.0003)
    Format: 3 1/2" Green IBM Imation 2HD Disk
    Capacity: 1.44 MB
  - "Zedd: 3 Maggot Stills", 2003; ID: 311.3.0004 (Box 12, Media ID: 311.3.0004)
    Format: 3 1/2" Green IBM Imation 2 HD Disk
  - "Zedd Maggot 2003", ID: 311.3.0005 (Box 12, Media ID: 311.3.0005)
    Format: 3 1/2" Blue IBM Imation 2HD Disk
  - [Kodak Picture Disk, 1 of 2], December 3, 2000; ID: 311.3.0006 (Box 12, Media ID: 311.3.0006)
    Format: 3 1/2" Red Kodak Disk
    Capacity: 8 MB
  - [Kodak Picture Disk, 2 of 2], December 3, 2000; ID: 311.3.0007 (Box 12, Media ID: 311.3.0007)
  - "Zedd on Set", July 2003; ID: 311.3.0008 (Box 12, Media ID: 311.3.0008)
  - [P.O. SHOUT Magazine], undated; ID: 311.3.0009 (Box 12, Media ID: 311.3.0009)
    Format: 3 1/2" Gray Iomega Disk
  - [Photography and Software], undated (Box 31)
    This is a collection of 12 CD-R assorted recordings from Zedd's personal files.
    Media ID: 311.0488 - 311.0494, 311.0498 - 311.0502
- OVERSIZE Series I: Writing
  - Subseries A: Zedd A - Z
    - Wallpaper Zine [Fragments, 1 of 2], c1983 - 1990 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Wallpaper Zine [Fragments, 2 of 2], c1983 - 1990 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - "War is Menstrual Envy" [Synopsis, Blue Scrapbook Cover], c1992 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B: Juvenelia
    - The Beacon Volume 9, Number 4 [High Point High School of Beltsville, MD], January 1963 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - The Beacon Volume 19, Number 4, December 14, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "Essay" by James Harding for Prattler Volume 39, Number 5, December 20, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Prattler Volume 41, Number 4, November 20, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Venusian Press [Sketches removed from XINE Sketchbook], 1969 - 1971 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Subseries C: Source and Subject Files
    - CMLL De Lucha Libre Official Calendar, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - [Comic Sketches of Nick Zedd and Taylor Mead], undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - [Lydia Lunch Posters], undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - [Johnny Rotten Poster], undated (Folder 1 Right)
    - [Willy Deville Poster], undated (Folder 2 Right)
  - Subseries D: Other Authors
    - "In Praise of Hardcore" by Kenneth Tynan, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - "Dream" by Casandra Stark for Underground Film Bulletin, June 28, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 2)
- OVERSIZE Series II: Projects
  - Subseries A: Development
    - "Destination X" [Sketches removed from "Johnny Satan" Sketchbook], c1977 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "Destination X" [Animation Cells], 1976 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - "Johnny Satan" [Sketches removed Black Sketchbook], c1976 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B: Distribution
    - "The Adventures of Electra Elf" [Posters], undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "The Adventures of Electra Elf" [Mock-Up Poster Prints for Incomplete Feature with Notes], c2009 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - "The Bogus Man" [Poster for East Village Eye], June 30, 1980 (Box Shared Fales 080, Folder 8)
    - [Flyers of Events Featuring Zedd 1], various (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - [Flyers of Events Featuring Zedd 2], various (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "Geek Maggot Bingo" [Flyers], 1983 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - "Geek Maggot Bingo" [Poster Illustration by T. Smith], 1982 (Folder 6 Right)
    - "Lord of the Cockrings" [Posters], 2001 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - "Me Minus You" [Flyers], 1985 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - [Nick Zedd at Beursschouwburg Program, Belgium], April 11 - 31, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - [Nick Zedd: Cinema of Transgression at Werkstattkino Malseh'n Program, Germany], March 1990 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - "No Such Thing As Gravity" [Posters], 1990 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Penetration Films [Case Graphics, Mock-Ups], undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - "Police State" [Flyers], c1987 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - "Police State" [Poster Illustration], c1987 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - [Poster Advertisements for Events Featuring Zedd], various (Folder 5 Right)
    - "The Raunchy World of Nick Zedd: Sleaze Cinema" [Poster], c1988 (Folder 10)
    - "Shadows in the City" [Posters], c1990 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - "Thrust in Me" [Mounted Self Portraits], 1998 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - "War is Menstrual Envy" [Poster Mock-Ups], 1992 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - "War is Menstrual Envy" [Mounted Stills 1], c1992 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - "War is Menstrual Envy" [Mounted Stills 2], c1992 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "War is Menstrual Envy" [Mounted Stills 3], c1992 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - "War is Menstrual Envy" [Mounted Stills 4], c1992 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Why Do You Exist" [Poster with Mounted Stills], 1998 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "Geek Maggot Bingo/The Adventures of Electra Elf: Vile Buddies" [Poster], c2006 (Folder 19)
    - "Nick Zedd Undergroundfilme aus New York" at Die Rohre Program [Germany], March 1990 (Folder 17)
  - Subseries E: Other Artists and Events
    - [Flyers of Events Not Featuring Zedd], various (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Giorno Poetry Systems AIDS Treatment Project Poster, undated (Folder 4 Right)
    - MOMA PS1 Newspaper, Spring 2009 (Folder 3 Right)
    - [Posters of Events Not Featuring Zedd], 1988, 1996 (Folder 18)
- OVERSIZE Series IV: Dad's Pornography Collection
  - [Assorted Posters], c1942, 1960s (Box 39, Folder 10)
- OVERSIZE Series V: Photography
  - Subseries A: Professional
    - [Donna Death Portraits], 1979 - 1983 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - [Monica Casanova Portraits], undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - [Press Photographs of Zedd], undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: Personal
    - [Mounted Halloween Photograph], November 24, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 1)
- OVERSIZE Series VI: Illustrations and Artwork
  - [Halloween Party Scene Illustration], undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - [Illustrations of Nick Zedd], undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - [Lucha Libre Sketch], undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - "Prevent Senseless Tragedy / Bizarreness of Fantasies of Grandville" [Painting], undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
- OVERSIZE Series VII: Objects
  - Subseries A: Props
    - "The Adventures of Electra Elf" ASS Magazine Styroboard Sign, 2002 - 2008 (Folder 1 Right)
  - Subseries B: Zedd - Casanova Clothing
    - [Green Pleated Mini Skirt with "Electra Elf" Screen Print], undated (Box 17, Object ID: 311.2.0013)
    - [White Sleeveless T-Shirt with "Electra Elf" Screen Print], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0014)
    - [Yellow Sweatshirt with "Electra Elf" Screen Print], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0015)
    - [Blue T-Shirt with "Electra Elf" Screen Print], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0016)
    - [Two Tan T-Shirts with "Electra Elf" Screen Print], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0017)
    - [Yellow Thermal Shirt with "Electra Elf" Screen Print], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0018)
    - [Red T-Shirt with "Cinema of Transgression, Volume 1" Patch], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0019)
    - [Black T-Shirt with "Cinema of Transgression, Volume 1" Patch], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0020)
    - [Pink Sweatshirt with "Whoregasm" Screen Print], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0021)
    - [Black T-Shirt with "Geek Maggot Bingo" Patch], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0022)
    - [Black Sweatshirt with "They Eat Scum" Patch], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0023)
    - [White Blouse with Zedd Filmography Prints], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0024)
    - [Yellow Blouse with Zedd Filmography Prints], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0025)
    - [Yellow Blouse with Zedd Filmography Prints], undated (Box 36, Object ID: 311.2.0026)
    - [Gray Pleated Skirt with Screen Print of Richard Hell], undated (Box 17, Object ID: 311.2.0027)
    - [Black Pleated Mini Skirt with "Geek Maggot Bingo" Screen Print], undated (Box 17, Object ID: 311.2.0028)
    - [Houndstooth Pleated Skirt with "Geek Maggot Bingo" Screen Print], undated (Box 17, Object ID: 311.2.0029)
    - [Maroon Pleated Mini Skirt with Screen Print of Richard Hell], undated (Box 17, Object ID: 311.2.0030)
    - [Green Pleated Skirt with Screen Print of Richard Hell], undated (Box 17, Object ID: 311.2.0031)
    - ["Geek Maggot Bingo" Brenda Bergman and Richard Hell Screenprint Stencil], undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - ["Geek Maggot Bingo" Donna Death Screenprint Stencil], undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - ["Geek Maggot Bingo" Richard Hell Screenprint Stencil], undated (Box 37, Object ID: 311.2.0035, Folder 1)
    - ["The Adventures of Electra Elf" Screenprint Stencil], undated (Box 38, Object ID: 311.2.0035)
    - [Zedd - Casanova Clothing Transparencies], undated (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Subseries C: The Mexican Kit (Box 40, Box 41, Box 42, Box 43, Box 44, Box 47, Box 45, Box 46, Folder 11, Folder 9 Left)
    - [Tapestry textile], undated (Folder 11, Object 311.2.0037)
    - [Paper cutouts], undated (Folder 9 Left, Object 311.2.0038)
    - [Chalice with red cloth], undated (Box 46, Object 311.2.0039)
    - [Decorative object with streamers], undated (Box 46, Object 311.2.0040)
    - [Metal candle stick], undated (Box 47, Object 311.2.0041)
    - [Glass pyramid], undated (Box 47, Object 311.2.0042)
    - [Skeleton virgin mary with glitter], undated (Box 47, Object 311.2.0043)
    - [Skeleton with glitter], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0044)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0045)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0046)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0047)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0048)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0049)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0050)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0051)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0052)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0053)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0054)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0055)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0056)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0057)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0058)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 40, Object 311.2.0059)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0060)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0061)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0062)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0063)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0064)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0065)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0066)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0067)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0068)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0069)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0070)
    - [Sugar skull], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0071)
    - [Hello kitty bandages], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0072)
    - [Skull figurine white], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0073)
    - [Skull figurine black], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0074)
    - [Cheetah mask wrestler], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0075)
    - [White, black, and red mask wrestler], undated (Box 41, Object 311.2.0076)
    - [Silver glitter masked wrestler], undated (Box 42, Object 311.2.0077)
    - [Striped silver masked wrestler], undated (Box 42, Object 311.2.0078)
    - [Black glitter masked wrestler], undated (Box 42, Object 311.2.0079)
    - [Pink glitter masked wrestler], undated (Box 42, Object 311.2.0080)
    - [Skeleton shrink wrapped], undated (Box 42, Object 311.2.0081)
    - [Grim reaper shrink wrapped], undated (Box 42, Object 311.2.0082)
    - [Female devil figurine], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0083)
    - [Male devil figurine], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0084)
    - [Plastic skeleton figurine], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0085)
    - [Wrestler figurine black with yellow cape], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0086)
    - [Wrestler figurine grey with black cape], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0087)
    - [Wrestler figurine black], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0088)
    - [Wrestler figurine blue], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0089)
    - [Wrestler figurine white pants], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0090)
    - [Wrestler figurine green pants], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0091)
    - [Wrestler figurine yellow pants], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0092)
    - [Wrestler figurine orange pants], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0093)
    - [Wrestler figurine pink pants], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0094)
    - [Wrestler figurine blue pants], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0095)
    - [Gold tinsel], undated (Box 43, Object 311.2.0096)
    - [Sugar sculpture], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0097)
    - [Skull string necklace], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0098)
    - [Resin disc], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0099)
    - [Bottle of fragrance oil], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0100)
    - [Vial of sand and shells], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0101)
    - [Santa Muerte cloth necklace], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0102)
    - [Wooden scythe], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0103)
    - [Rosary necklace], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0104)
    - [Pearl and crystal necklace], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0105)
    - [Pendant on cord necklace], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0106)
    - [Plastic grapes], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0107)
    - [Rock fragment], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0108)
    - [Blue glass pebble], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0109)
    - [Felt with skeleton embroidery], undated (Box 44, Object 311.2.0110)
    - [Painting on metal], undated (Box 45, Object 311.2.0111)